http://www.superjeweler.com/cp/index/terms-of-use.html#sj-cockes

Cufflinks
USD ($)
AUD ($)
CAD ($)
EUR (€)
GBP (£)
NZD ($)
CHF (CHF)
JPY (¥)
MXN ($)
SEK (kr )
CNY (¥)
HKD ($)
TERMS OF USE
Welcome to SuperJeweler.com.
The following page contains our Terms of Use for www.SuperJeweler.com (the "Website"). Yes, this is the legal mumbo-jumbo. We don't like it either, and we've tried to make them readable, but we have to put this stuff in here. But PLEASE, feel free to call us at (877) 888-0175 if you have any questions about anything in these Terms of Use. We've tried to make this process easy to use so we have provided quick links to specific topics within the Terms of Use.
Quick Links
Terms of Use
Who May Use Our Website
SuperJeweler.com Lifetime Gurantee, Return, Refund And Shipping Policies
FOB Shipping
SuperJeweler.com's Enduring Quality Guarantee
Pricing
Return Procedures
Manner of Refunds
Return Shipping
Undelivered Products
Information Regarding Our Products
Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating
Catalog, Newsletters, Etc.
Surveys & Sweepstakes
Special Offers
Choice/Opt-Out
Third Party Content And Product
External Links
Our Advertising Partners
Other Terms Of Use
Affiliate Marketing
Terms of Use
SuperJeweler.com (we, us and our) developed and maintains the Website and currently allows access to the Website free-of-charge to users who agree to abide by the terms and conditions of this Agreement. We operate our website and do business in the State of New York, County of Manhattan. By doing business with us you agree that all disputes, regardless of whether we are the plaintiff or defendant will be settled in a court of competent jurisdiction for the County of Manhattan. We reserve the right to change the nature of this relationship at any time, and to revise these guidelines and Terms of Use from time to time as we deem necessary. Any user that violates the terms of this Agreement will have their access canceled and they may permanently be banned from using the Site and any interactive services that we offer. You should check these terms and conditions periodically. By using the Site after we post changes to these Terms of Use, you agree to accept those changes, whether or not you actually reviewed them. Entering the Website will constitute your acceptance of these Terms of Use.
Back to Quick Links
Who May Use Our Website
We encourage all person over the age of eighteen to enjoy the Site and we do not discriminate on the basis of age, race, national origin, gender, sexual orientation or religion. No person under the age of 18 should use the Website. We strongly encourage all parents and guardians to monitor the Internet use of their children. Use of the Website by any user shall be deemed to be a representation that the user is 18 years of age or older.
Back to Quick Links
SUPERJEWELER.COM LIFETIME GUARANTEE, RETURN, REFUND AND SHIPPING POLICIES
FOB Shipping
All shipments from SuperJeweler.com and/or it’s affiliates, designees or assigns are shipped to customers/purchasers FOB Origin. This means that as of the moment that SuperJeweler, it’s affiliates, designees or assigns have tendered (given) your package to the shipping company, the ownership, control, and risk of loss of the package is transferred to you, the customer/purchaser. All responsibility and liability rests with the recipient of packages, as SuperJeweler ships FOB Origin. SuperJeweler is not liable for losses in transit or at the destination.
The theft of packages at the place of delivery, also known at Porch Piracy or Porch Pirates, is solely the responsibility of the customer/purchaser/recipient.
Back to Quick Links
SuperJeweler.com's Enduring Quality Guarantee
All purchases from SuperJeweler.com come with SuperJeweler.com's Enduring Quality Guarantee. Your SuperJeweler.com jewelry purchase includes a lifetime warranty against the loss of side stones or damage to the jewelry's setting or center stone. It also includes a one-year replacement guarantee against the loss of your jewelry's center stone.
If you ever lose a side stone from your jewelry, SuperJeweler.com will replace that side stone with a stone of similar quality. If your setting is ever damaged, SuperJeweler.com will repair or replace the setting or center stone, at its sole discretion, at no cost to you. If you lose a side stone or your setting is damaged, you must send the piece back to SuperJeweler.com, along with your original purchase receipt or, if you are unable to provide the original purchase receipt, include the name of the original purchaser and the approximate date of purchase. If your center stone is lost from its original setting within one (1) year of purchase, SuperJeweler.com will replace the stone. If your center stone is ever chipped or broken, in its original setting, SuperJeweler.com will replace the stone with one equal in quality and value to your original stone. If you lose your center stone within one (1) year of purchase, or if your center stone is ever chipped or broken, you must send the piece back to SuperJeweler.com, along with your original purchase receipt. Shipping details are listed below.
This warranty does not cover damage to jewelry other than that incurred in normal wear. This warranty does not cover lost jewelry. You must provide identifiable pieces of the jewelry in order for SuperJeweler.com to honor this warranty. If SuperJeweler.com determines that it did not manufacture the original piece it is under no obligation to honor this warranty. Improper repair or service performed by a third party other than SuperJeweler.com will void this warranty. This warranty is non-transferrable. All warranty claims under the SuperJeweler.com Enduring Quality Guarantee must be made by the original purchaser or the original gift recipient. This warranty does not cover losses or damage by any successor owner of the jewelry, including but not limited second-hand purchasers, heirs or assigns. This warranty does not cover damage to jewelry other than that incurred in normal wear. This warranty does not cover lost jewelry.
Back to Quick Links
Pricing
We make every attempt to avoid errors in pricing and product information, but we are human. If a mistake does occur, we reserve the right to correct it, and we apologize for any inconvenience it may cause. All prices listed on this site are in U.S. dollars.
Back to Quick Links
Return Procedures
SuperJeweler.com has a 60-day money back guarantee policy. This is a simple process and is described fully in our 60-day money back guarantee. To see the complete list of procedures for returning merchandise please visit the SuperJeweler.com FAQs section of this website, reachable from the Website's homepage.
Back to Quick Links
Manner of Refunds
Unless specifically requested, and authorized by us, refunds will be issued in the same manner as payment was received.
Back to Quick Links
Return Shipping
Please send your jewelry, along with the required proof of purchase, to 7 W. 45th St., 10th Floor, New York, New York, 10036. You are responsible for the costs associated with shipping and insuring your jewelry for shipment back to SuperJeweler.com. Upon replacement of a stone or upon repair or replacement of the setting SuperJeweler.com will ship the piece back to you and will cover all costs associated with shipping and insuring the piece.
Back to Quick Links
Undelivered Products
We understand that you want to get your order a quickly as possible, but unfortunately sometimes there is a delay caused by the carrier used to deliver products. Because of this we have a 15-business-day waiting period before any product will be resent.
Back to Quick Links
INFORMATION REGARDING OUR PRODUCTS
Product Images
We have attempted to accurately depict the colors of the products offered on this site. Because the color you see is dependent on your computer monitor we cannot guarantee that the color you see will be accurate. The products also may appear larger or smaller than their actual size depending on your monitor. Some photographs have been enlarged to show detail. If you are not satisfied that with your purchase, all jewelry comes with a 60-day money back guarantee detailed below.
Back to Quick Links
Stone Weight Range
SuperJeweler.com carefully measures carat weights ("ct") but, by purchasing jewelry from the Site, you agree that the advertised carat weight may vary slightly and that SuperJeweler.com is not liable for any actual or consequential damages associated with claims of such variances. The range of actual carat weight for the advertised carat weight is as follows:
1/10ct means .08ct to .12ct
1/8ct means .10ct to .14ct
1/6ct means .13ct to .18ct
1/5ct means .16ct to .23ct
1/4ct means .22ct to .29ct
1/3ct means .28ct to .35ct
3/8ct means .34ct to .42ct
1/2ct means .44ct to .60ct
Stone Enhancement
A diamond's color or clarity can be enhanced using certain techniques (such as heating). SuperJeweler.com offers such color-enhanced diamonds on this Website. If a diamond for sale on the Site is color-enhanced, the product description will clearly state that it has been color-enhanced. Please click the following link for gemstone disclosures and production descriptions for the gemstones that we sell. Gemstone Disclosure
Back to Quick Links
Stone and Metal Grading
The stones and metal have been graded for quality and listed on the Website according to industry standards. Aside from the right to return jewelry under the 60-day money back guarantee, SuperJeweler.com is not liable for any actual or consequential damages associated with the grading of stones or gold offered on the Website.
Back to Quick Links
Restriction Against Component Resale
We are in the business of selling products to the persons that will use them. If you plan to resell our products please give us a call. Since this is a retail website we require that the customer agree that they will not engage in the business of reselling components purchased from SuperJeweler.com, or remove components from product for resale, except upon express prior written authorization of SuperJeweler.com. Any resale of product or components will void all guarantees and warranties.
Back to Quick Links
Sale of Jewelry From Third Parties
SuperJeweler.com occasionally offers products from third party vendors. SuperJeweler.com is unable to guarantee karatage/stone weights on such products.
Back to Quick Links
CUSTOMER ACCOUNTS
Creating Your Account
When you make your first purchase on the Website, you will be asked to create an account. By creating an account, the system will remember your personal and purchase information and the checkout process on future purchases will be fast, easy and always completely secure.
Creating an account is also fast and easy: simply enter your personal information once and select your very own username and password. Then during checkout on your next purchase, just login and the system will take care of the rest. At all times, your personal information is accessible to you to review, edit, or update as necessary by clicking on the "My Account" link.
Back to Quick Links
Placing Orders
We request information from the user on our order form when making a purchase. Here is what a user must provide: 1) their contact information, like name and shipping address, and 2) financial information, like credit card number and expiration date. This information is used for billing purposes and to fill the customer's order. If we have difficulty processing an order, this contact information is used to communicate with the customer.
Back to Quick Links
Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code, phone, e-mail or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate that user's personally identifiable information provided to us.
Back to Quick Links
Catalog, Newsletters, Etc.
If a user wishes to subscribe to our catalog, newsletter, etc., we ask for contact information such as name, street address and e-mail address to provide these communications. Because we respect our users' privacy, we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the choice and opt-out section below. On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send you an e-mail. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though you can deactivate your account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.
Back to Quick Links
Surveys & Sweepstakes
From time to time, our site requests information from users via surveys or sweepstakes. Participation in these surveys or sweepstakes is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name, shipping address and e-mail address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.
Back to Quick Links
Special Offers
Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special offers and a newsletter by e-mail. Out of respect for the privacy of our users, we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below.
Back to Quick Links
Choice/Opt-Out
Users who no longer wish to receive promotional materials may opt-out of receiving these communications by using the unsubscribe feature in our e-mail.
Back to Quick Links
THIRD PARTY CONTENT AND PRODUCT
External Links
Please be aware that we may provide links to third party websites from this website as a service to our users and we are not responsible for the content or information collection practices of those sites. We have no ability to control the privacy and data collection practices of such sites and the privacy policies of such sites may differ from that of SuperJeweler.com. Therefore, we encourage you to review and understand the privacy policies of such sites before providing them with any information. SuperJeweler.com assumes no liability for any damages you may suffer from visiting such linked websites, including without limitation, damages caused by computer viruses, Trojan Horses or other destructive/disruptive code which may be downloaded from such linked websites. Any links contained on this website shall not be construed as an endorsement by SuperJeweler.com of any such linked website. SuperJeweler.com has not reviewed or researched the full content on these linked websites and shall not be held responsible should you encounter any materials that may appear inaccurate, indecent or illegal. If you visit such a website that is linked to this website, please contact us and we will determine if the link should be removed from the Website.
Back to Quick Links
Our Advertising Partners
For some products that we offer we have teamed up with leading companies to bring you quality services and products. Our reference to them as an Advertising Partner does not mean that we are partners with these companies in the legal sense, merely that we are working with them to offer products and services to you. All companies that we feature on our site are solely responsible for their own obligations to you and while we are not legally responsible for their obligations, be assured that we will always assist you in dealing with them should any issues arise.
Back to Quick Links
OTHER TERMS OF USE
Affiliate Marketing
SuperJeweler.com actively markets its products through affiliate campaigns and, from time to time, offers coupons through such affiliates. Offers through affiliates may vary. SuperJeweler.com also does last-click-attribution in order to properly compensate its affiliate marketers.
Back to Quick Links
Requirements for SuperJeweler.com Monthly Giveaways
Winners of any contests or giveaways on the Website agree to provide SuperJeweler.com with a photograph of themselves for publicity purposes, to be posted on the Website or on various social media websites. SuperJeweler.com will not publish winners' full names; only the first name to protect winners' privacy. Failure by a winner of a contest or giveaway to provide a photograph of themselves may result in the forfeiture of any prize won.
Back to Quick Links
Your Privacy Rights – How We Protect Your Information
We are very concerned about privacy matters for our customers and have a separate section of our website devoted entirely to our policy regarding protecting your policy. Please review our Privacy Policy. By using our website you are also agreeing to abide by our Privacy Policy.
Back to Quick Links
Taxes
Prices on the website do not include sales tax or any other customs duties, use, value added, excise, federal, state, local or other taxes. New York residents will be charged sales tax, but all other such duties or taxes shall be paid by you, or, in lieu thereof, customer shall provide us with an appropriate tax exemption certificate.
Back to Quick Links
Restrictions on Use of Copyrights and Trademarks
This Website and all materials on the Website, including, but not limited to the sales copy, navigational aids, images, illustrations, and logos are either our or our affiliates' and licencors' property and are protected from unauthorized copying and distribution by copyright law, trademark law, international conventions and other intellectual property laws. If you desire to use these properties, you must obtain our written consent prior to your use.
Back to Quick Links
Disclaimer of Liability
In no event shall we be liable for any indirect, special, incidental or consequential damages.
Back to Quick Links
Assignment
Customer may not assign its rights or obligations hereunder without the express prior written consent of SuperJeweler.com .
Back to Quick Links
Severability of Sections
If any of these conditions shall be deemed invalid, void, or for any reason unenforceable, that condition shall be deemed severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any remaining condition.
Back to Quick Links
Changes to these Terms of Use
We will occasionally update these Terms of Use to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we post changes to these Terms of Use, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of these Terms of Use. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share personal information that may impact you, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us in your account, profile or registration (unless we do not have such an e-mail address), and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website. We recommend that you check our websites from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in these Terms of Use.
Back to Quick Links
Incorporation of Privacy Policy
The SuperJeweler.com Privacy Policy, posted on the Website, is incorporated in its entirety and by reference into these Terms of Use.
Back to Quick Links
Entire Agreement
These terms and conditions constitute the entire agreement between SuperJeweler.com and the customer regarding any sale. These terms expressly supersede and replace any prior or contemporaneous agreements, whether written or oral, relating to said sale, including any terms and conditions on any of customer's documents or purchase orders. ANY ADDITIONAL, DIFFERENT OR CONFLICTING TERMS AND CONDITIONS ON ANY SUCH DOCUMENT ISSUED BY CUSTOMER AT ANY TIME ARE HEREBY OBJECTED TO BY SUPERJEWELER.COM, AND ANY SUCH DOCUMENT SHALL BE WHOLLY INAPPLICABLE TO ANY SALE MADE HEREUNDER AND SHALL NOT BE BINDING IN ANY WAY ON SUPERJEWELER.COM. This agreement shall be binding upon the heirs, successors and assigns of the parties hereto. If any provision of this agreement shall be held to be invalid or unenforceable, the remainder of this agreement shall remain in full force and effect.
Back to Quick Links
Updated March 1, 2012
PRIVACY POLICY
This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices surrounding your use of the Website and our use of information you provide during your customer experience on the Website. We are committed to protecting your privacy and encourage you to periodically review this page to be informed of how we protect the information you disclose to us.
If you believe that SuperJeweler.com is not abiding by our posted privacy policy, please contact us at 1-877-888-01751-877-888-0175 or e-mail us at sales@superjeweler.com
Back to Quick Links
INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE
SuperJeweler.com is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. SuperJeweler.com collects information from our users at several different points on our website.
Back to Quick Links
Cookies
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. The Cookies are used to keep track of your shopping cart and if you have become a member, will remember your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Website. (Note – when we say password we mean your password to our membership site, NOT to your computer or e-mail account). We use both session and persistent cookies. Usage of a cookie from the Website is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information. Cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users in the aggregate by analyzing popular areas and products to enhance future experiences on our site. Cookies do not cause damage to your computer systems or files, and only the website that transferred a particular cookie to you can read, modify or delete such cookie. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there are simple procedures in most browsers that allow you to delete existing cookies, to automatically decline cookies, or to be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer of particular cookies to your computer.
Back to Quick Links
Usage Tracking
SuperJeweler.com's database tracks the traffic throughout our site. This information is used to compile overall statistics and is not recorded at an individual level. This includes IP (internet protocol) addresses, browser type, ISP (internet service provider), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate. The statistics help us decide which products and services best serve our members and guests.
Back to Quick Links
Aggregate Information
SuperJeweler.com uses aggregate information from demographic surveys, traffic patterns and IP addresses to customize our site. Aggregate information is occasionally shared with partners third parties for purposes such as planning or executing advertising or promotions. We do not share any personally identifiable information.
Back to Quick Links
Sharing
SuperJeweler.com gives you access to third party partners to provide you with certain services that are detailed below. SuperJeweler.com will provide that third party with your transaction information and then that third party will collect additional information if needed to provide you with the requested service, such as outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services.
We reserve the right to transfer any and all information that we collect from users of the site to a third party in the event of any merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of the assets or stock (including without limitation in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings) relating to SuperJeweler.com.
Finally, notwithstanding any other provision of this privacy policy to the contrary, we reserve the right to disclose your personal information if we believe that we are required to do so (i) by law; (ii) to comply with legal process or governmental requests; (iii) to enforce our Terms of Use; (iv) to protect our operations or those of any affiliated entities; (v) to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of SuperJeweler.com, any affiliated entities, you or others; and (vi) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.
Back to Quick Links
Supplementation of Information
In order for SuperJeweler.com to properly fulfill its obligation to our customers, it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from third party sources such as our affiliated websites. For example, in order for SuperJeweler.com to enhance our ability to tailor the site to an individual's preference, we combine information about the purchasing habits of users with similar information from our affiliated sites and SuperJeweler.com. When a user makes a purchase from any of these companies, the companies collect and share that purchase information with us so we can tailor the site to our users' preferences.
Back to Quick Links
New Product Offerings
In its pursuit of constantly offering new and innovative products, SuperJeweler.com may, at some point in the future offer products other than Jewelry, and may offer such products through websites other than the Website. Any and all information you provide to SuperJeweler.com may be shared with such other affiliated businesses.
Back to Quick Links
SECURITY
SuperJeweler.com takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via our website, your information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - Secure Socket Layers (SSLs). While on a secure page, such as our order form, a lock icon appears on the bottom of your Web browser. When you are not on a secure page, no lock icon will appear. In addition, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment under restricted access.
If you have any questions about the security of our website, send us an e-mail at sales@superjeweler.com for more info.
Back to Quick Links
OTHER TERMS OF THE SUPERJEWELER.COM PRIVACY POLICY
Changes to This Policy
We reserve the right to change this privacy policy, and any of our policies or procedures concerning the treatment of information collected through the site, without prior notice. You can determine when this privacy policy was last revised by referring to date at the top of this page. Any changes to our privacy policy will become effective upon posting of the revised policy on the Internet, accessible through the site. Use of the site following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised policy then in effect. We encourage you to periodically review our privacy policy to ensure familiarity with our most current version.
Back to Quick Links
SuperJeweler.com, Inc Communications
When
you supply SuperJeweler.com, Inc with your mobile phone number, from
time-to-time, in SuperJeweler.com, Inc's discretion, you may be asked to
indicate whether you are interested in receiving alert notification for
when upgrades go live via email and/or SMS text messaging. Where you
authorize us to we may, from time to time, send you such marketing
communications.
If
you sign up to receive promotional materials from us via email we will
use the information you give us to provide the communications you have
requested. If you inform us that you wish to cancel email promotional
materials by selecting “unsubscribe” at the bottom of such communication
or by emailing us at unsubscribe@SuperJeweler.com, Inc.com, we will remove you from our mailing list.
You
may opt out of any alerts by replying with the text "STOP" to such
alert or sending the message "STOP" in the text message you received .
If you send the text "STOP", you will no longer receive any text
messages including, without limitation, advance notices of ticket sales.
After you send the SMS message "STOP" to us, we will send you an SMS
message to confirm you have been unsubscribed. After this, you will no
longer receive SMS messages from us.
We
will make every attempt to remove your mobile telephone number from the
SuperJeweler.com, Inc text database as soon as possible, but please
allow up to ten (10) days. If we already provided your information to a
third party (such as an event provider or insurance company or shipping
company) before you changed your preferences or updated your
information, you may have to change your preferences directly with that
third party as well.
For additional help, email sales@SuperJeweler.com, Inc.com. If you are unable to send a text message, you agree that you will send an email to sales@SuperJeweler.com, Inc.com with the subject line of "STOP" along with your mobile number in the subject heading of the email.
Back to Quick Links
GEMSTONE DISCLOSURES
Black Diamonds
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Product Description
Natural black diamonds extremely rare. SuperJeweler sells only heat treated black diamonds, treated with the High Pressure Heat Treatment (HPHT) method. In HPHT treatment, white included poor quality diamonds are heated to approximately 1260 degrees Fahrenheit, in a reducing atmosphere, meaning under the conditions of very little oxygen, and the unpleasant white and included diamonds become black. HPHT treatment is completely safe, and produces gem quality black diamonds.
Back to Quick Links
Blue Diamonds
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Product Description
Natural untreated blue diamonds do exist, such as the Hope Diamond, they are extraordinarily rare and very expensive. SuperJeweler's blue diamonds are safely irradiated in a cyclotron or linear accelerator, followed by a heat treatment, that turns brownish and pale yellow diamonds into richly colored, affordable blue diamonds. This color change to blue is permanent, but can change if the diamond is exposed to high heat. SuperJeweler's blue diamonds are beautiful and safe to wear.
Back to Quick Links
Ruby
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Ruby, a member of the corundum family of gemstones, is generally red in color, from light pink to dark red. The most common treatment for the enhancement of color is heat treating. In the heat treating process, rough un-cut rubies are heated to 1700-1800 degrees celsius, which improves both color and clarity. All rubies that SuperJeweler sells are heat treated for the enhancement of red color and clarity.
Back to Quick Links
Created Ruby
Stone-creation-method is synthetic
Stone-treatment-method is Not-treated
Lab-created Yes
Product Description
Some items contains a lab-created ruby, created with the Flame Fusion method. Flame Fusion lab-created synthetic rubies are a beautiful red color and have excellent clarity, and are very affordable. Lab-created rubies have the same properties as natural rubies, but are man-made in a laboratory.
Back to Quick Links
Sapphire
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Sapphire, a member of the corundum family of gemstones, is generally blue in color, from cornflower blue Ceylon sapphires, to dark blue Australian sapphires, to bright royal blue Burmese sapphires, and everything in between. The most common treatment for the enhancement of color is heat treating. In the heat treating process, rough un-cut sapphires are heated to 1700-1800 degrees Celsius, which improves both color and clarity. All sapphires that SuperJeweler sells are heat treated for the enhancement of blue color and clarity.
Back to Quick Links
Created Sapphire
Stone-creation-method is synthetic
Stone-treatment-method is Not-treated
Lab-created Yes
Product Description
Some items contains a lab-created sapphire, created with the Flame Fusion method. Flame Fusion lab-created synthetic sapphires are a beautiful blue color and have excellent clarity, and are very affordable. Lab-created sapphires have the same properties as natural sapphires, but are man-made in a laboratory.
Back to Quick Links
Emerald
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is oiled
Lab-created No
Product Description
Emerald, a member of the beryl family of gemstones, is generally green in color, famously the deep emerald green of Columbian emeralds, but available from light pea green to dark green with black gardening. Inclusions in emeralds are referred to as garden. The most common treatment for the enhancement of color is oiling. In the standard oiling process, emeralds are immersed in colorless oil or resin, inside a vacuum chamber to gain better penetration into the stone. Newer treatments go further, with the introduction of green colored oils and hard epoxy resin to improve color and clarity. All emeralds that SuperJeweler sells are oiled for the enhancement of green color and clarity. Some emeralds that SuperJeweler sells have resins introduced to improve clarity.
Back to Quick Links
Created Emerald
Stone-creation-method is synthetic
Stone-treatment-method is Not-treated
Lab-created Yes
Product Description
Some item contains a lab-created emerald, created with the Flux Fusion or Hydrothermal method. Flux Fusion and Hydrothermal lab-created synthetic emeralds are beautiful in color and have excellent clarity, and are very affordable. Lab-created emeralds have the same properties as natural emeralds, but are man-made in a laboratory.
Back to Quick Links
Created Pink Sapphire
Stone-creation-method is synthetic
Stone-treatment-method is Not-treated
Lab-created Yes
Product Description
Some items contains a lab-created pink sapphire, created with the Flame Fusion method. Flame Fusion lab-created synthetic pink sapphires are a beautiful pink color and have excellent clarity, and are very affordable. Lab- created pink sapphires have the same properties as natural pink sapphires, but are man-made in a laboratory.
Back to Quick Links
Tanzanite
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Tanzanite is part of the zoisite group of gemstones. One of the most recent gemstones discovered, tanzanite was discovered in Tanzania in 1967. The most popular color is a pretty blue, with a purplish hue. Tanzanites are heat treated to a temperature of 400-500 degrees Celsius, which eliminates brownish and yellowish tints. All tanzanites that SuperJeweler sells are heat treated to enhance the blue color.
Back to Quick Links
Blue Topaz
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is irradiated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Blue topaz is a member of the topaz gemstone family. While blue topaz occurs naturally, most blue topaz on the market today is made from white topaz that is irradiated to become a blue color. This process produces a gemstone that is from sky blue to dark blue in color, sometimes showing a greenish blue, and is not harmful to wear. All blue topaz that SuperJeweler sells is irradiated.
Back to Quick Links
Pink Topaz
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is Coated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Pink topaz is made from white topaz that is coated pink by using the vapor deposition method, patented by Azotic Coating Technologies. While the pink coating on pink topaz is durable, exposing the gemstone to intense heat can cause the color to fade. All pink topaz sold by SuperJeweler is enhanced with the vapor deposition method.
Back to Quick Links
Mystic Topaz
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is Coated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Mystic topaz is made from white topaz that is coated greenish purplish color by using the vapor deposition method, patented by Azotic Coating Technologies. While the greenish purplish coating on mystic topaz is durable, exposing the gemstone to intense heat or buffing by a jeweler can cause the color to fade or peel. All mystic topaz sold by SuperJeweler is enhanced with the vapor deposition method.
Back to Quick Links
Amethyst
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is not-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Amethyst is a member of the quartz family. Amethyst sold by SuperJeweler is natural and not treated.
Back to Quick Links
Green Amethyst
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Green amethyst is a member of the quartz family. Green amethyst sold by SuperJeweler is made from natural purple amethyst that is heat treated and turns a pretty green color. All green amethyst sold by SuperJeweler is heat treated.
Back to Quick Links
Lemon Quartz
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is Irradiated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Lemon Quartz is a member of the quartz family. Lemon Quartz sold by SuperJeweler is made from natural yellow quartz that is irradiated with gamma radiation, and turns a pretty yellow color. Gamma radiation treatment of gemstones is harmless to people, and there is no cooling period needed. This is the same type of radiation that is used to sterilized foods. All lemon quartz sold by SuperJeweler is irradiated.
Back to Quick Links
Garnet
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is not-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Garnet sold by SuperJeweler is natural and not treated.
Back to Quick Links
Citrine
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Citrine is a member of the quartz family. Citrine sold by SuperJeweler is made from natural amethyst that is heat treated and turns a pretty yellow color. All citrine sold by SuperJeweler is heat treated.
Back to Quick Links
Aquamarine
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is heat-treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Aquamarine is a member of the beryl family. Most aquamarines are heat treated at 400-450 degrees Celsius to enhance the stone to the popular blue-green color. All aquamarines sold by SuperJeweler are heat treated.
Back to Quick Links
Pearl
Pearl Type Freshwater-Cultured
Lustre  Medium-Luster
Surface Markings and Blemishes: Lightly Blemished
Product Description
All pearls sold by SuperJeweler are freshwater cultured and produced in China.
Back to Quick Links
Opal
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is Impregnated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Opals are generally white in color with colorful rainbow hues. Common treatments are impregnation with oil, resin, or plastic. All opals SuperJeweler sells are all enhanced and impregnated with oil and/or resin.
Back to Quick Links
Peridot
Stone-creation-method is natural
Stone-treatment-method is Not-Treated
Lab-created No
Product Description
Peridot is a member of the forsterite-fayalite mineral series. There are no know enhancements of peridot to improve its color or clarity. SuperJeweler sells natural, untreated peridot.
Back to Quick Links
Why Shop SuperJeweler
Lifetime Guarantee
Money-Back Guarantee
Monthly Diamond Studs Giveaway
About Us
How Can We Help You?
Contact Us
SuperJeweler Financing
Shipping Policy
Returns And Refunds
F.A.Q.
Copyright © 1999-2020. SuperJeweler.com. All rights reserved
